Dear Hiring Manager,

I would like to apply for the vacancy, and enclose my curriculum vitae for your consideration. I may not have the said fields qualification and experience but I am very interested to the post and I believe that I can do it with my willing to learn attitude.

I have been working in shipping industries for the past 9 years and I have learned a lot from my bosses, colleagues and consumers. However, it is time to accept new challenges. I am a very self-motivated person and I have a very strong desire to expand further more on my knowledge as well as my skills and experience.

I am confident to take on this position and I strongly believe that I am the most suitable candidate.

Please take a moment to review my attached resume.

My Resume

Computer Literacy and Other Skill

Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Carpentry work

Language

Spoken: English, Mandarin and Bahasa Indonesia Written: English, Chinese and Bahasa Indonesia

Personal Interests

Swimming, Reading books, Jogging, Gaming, Singing and Sports activities.

Academic Background

June 2004 – July 2005	Diploma in Business Washington Business School, Singapore
July 2005 – June 2006	Advanced Diploma in Business Washington Business School, Singapore
Nov 2006 – June 2007	Bachelor Degree in International Business James Cook University, Australia (Singapore Campus)

Job Objective

To obtain a challenging position with opportunity and growth.

Working Experience

Position : Sales Coordinator cum Customer Service

Company : LittleBow Tots (Self-Employed)
Period : September 2018 – till now 2022

Responsibilities

- Purchase and liaise with overseas seller on goods delivery.
- Sourcing overseas seller and ensure accurate order are deliver on time
- Attending to customer inquiries pertaining to collection, delivery, goods defect and complaints.
- Work closely with overseas agent for shipment delivery
- Generating invoice for customers.
- Prepare invoice and packing list.
- Monitor and follow-on COD / refund payment
- Packing and arranging delivery with local courier
- Process and upload order on online platform.

Position : Operation Executive (Export)
Company : Kuehne + Nagel Pte Ltd
Period : April 2016 – August 2018

- ➤ Efficient and smooth handling of shipment Preparation on bill of lading, Certificate of origin, SICC and outbound documents.
- Coordinate with various transporter, related parties for shipment scheduling and document Preparation.
- Execute day-to-day operational activities according to customer requirement and KPI.
- > Liaise with in-house department, shipping carrier and co-loaders to perform booking and collection.
- Prepare timely and accurate invoicing to customers.

- ► Handling of export shipment and transport arrangement.
- Verify vendor's invoice and ensure accurate costing input to system.
- Upload accurate outbound documents into customer system on timely.
- Sourcing of space for FCL and LCL to meet customer requirements.
- Closing of profit & Loss statement within monthly basis.
- Notify warehouse on arrival of shipment and schedule for transshipment.
- Coordinate and liaise with customers for stuffing, unstuffing, fumigation and shipment pick up.
- Monitor incoming shipment and arrange for outgoing / transshipment to destination port.
- Arrange to collect payment / COD customer.
- Arrange to courier document to the agent / customer.

Reason for leaving: Relocation

Position : Senior Customer Service Executive

Company : GLE Logistics (S) Pte Ltd Period : April 2012 – April 2016

- Preparation of bill of lading, shipping invoice / packing list, take out insurance risk coverage and perform necessarily declaration and clearance procedures.
- Arranging import, export, cross-trade and transhipment by sea, air or land transportation modes.
- Liaising with transporters, contractors, carriers/co-loaders, agents and freight forwarders to support timely receipt and delivery of shipments.
- Responsible to apply for MSCT permit and submitting deposit cheque to management before carrying out on packing / unpacking / collection / delivery job.
- Responsible to source for rates from various Carriers and to quote clients in timely manner.
- Liaison with shipping lines / agent for booking, pick-up and deliveries.
- To verify contractors, carriers and agents for costing and invoicing customers for payment.
- Liaise with shippers / consignee and customers for shipment arrangement.
- > Handle logistics arrangements by liaising with internal / external warehouse, 3rd party hub and forwarders.

- Maintain and update shipping schedule report to customers in timely manner.
- Coordination of insurance / surveyors and filling of marine cargo claims.
- Providing alternative transport solutions for client.
- Ensure fulfilment of customers' shipment on time, follow-up on collection, delivery and provide update to customers regarding shipment status.
- Monitor shipments status, keep inform and delays to appropriate parties / customers.
- Monitor and control the process of job completion and other ad hoc duties as assigned.

Reason for leaving: Company Restructuring

Position : Customer Service

Company : Dimerco Express Singapore Pte Ltd

Period : April 2010 - March 2012

- Handle all enquiries on customers on freight matter, coordinate on shipment status, Sales quotation and shipping advice and correspondences and when necessarily.
- > Generate billings on timely basis based on quotation or RFQ rate and ensure all billing to customers are correct and in compliance with agreed contractual terms and conditions.
- Process insurance policy, Certificate of Origin and advice correct billing to operations to bill customers accordingly.
- > Resolve client disputes, shipment irregularities, and customer's complaints.
- Coordinate with the respective internal and counterpart station on all incoming and outgoing shipment picked and delivered billing, and freight booking.
- Submission of customers' daily, weekly and monthly report and proactive shipment track and trace.
- Responsible to telemarketing for targeting prospective clients.
- Receive and confirm booking for local customer.
- > Schedule and coordinate with operations team to expedite deliveries to customer for urgent shipment.
- Monitor and update shipment movement & detail from the shipper's warehouse till consignee's door.
- Arrangement of courier service, network service to dispatch shipping document including full set prealert and correct billing to customers respectively.

- Coordination of the account receivable function ensuring customers are contacted when their payment are overdue and followed up for details of when they will bring their account current (Whenever necessarily)
- > Support for overseas agents and station enquiries by providing quotation, confirm booking and freight matter.
- > Updating all quotation in request E-Sam system for checking and billing purposes by Operation and Customer Service Team's
- Provided system and work training for new employees when necessarily.
- > Other Adhoc duties and work as assigned from time to time.

Samsung In House Support

- Maintain accurate supplier and materials part details in the SAP system to ensure stock availability.
- Update accurate AWB / BL detail in the glonet system in timely manner.
- Liaise and work closely with other freight forwarders, operations, warehouse's to ensure correct shipping orders, shipping mode request and picked and delivered to customers.
- Timely follow- up with suppliers to ensure arrivals of materials as required delivery date and coordinate with operation teams of shipment movement.
- Ensure proper implementation of SOPs between customers, purchasers and Business planner to enable a smooth working process in line with client expectations.
- Process SR request in the SAP system and advice to internal to proceed the shipment accordingly.
- Co-ordinate with various internal and external counterpart on booking and collection of cargo.
- Liaise and work closely with other freight forwarders, operations, warehouse's to ensure correct shipping orders, shipping mode request and picked and delivered to customers.

Reason for leaving: Lack of Career Advancement Opportunities

Position : Material management coordinator Company : Ceva Logistic Singapore Pte Ltd Period : September 2009 - March 2010

Responsibilities

Manage supplier follow up; contacting/communication with suppliers to make sure they are shipping to customers' firm orders, schedules or releases.

- Reporting and communicating supplier not shipping to schedule receive to client.
- Report and record any noncompliance with valid variance comments and reason code in the system.
- Following customer's business rules for under, over, and shipment issues.
- Responsible for communicating potential on time delivery issues to customer controllers regardless of faults, carrier and firms' issues.
- Maintain accurate supplier and materials part details in the internal system.
- Primary contact for suppliers, customer's material follow-up personnel and other service providers.
- Coordinates and follow up on expedite shipments.
- Reporting any noncompliance issue to supervisor to follow customer's compliance management process.
- Maintain proper documentations and filing.
- Maintain timely and accurate system transactions.
- Provided system training for new employees.
- Responsible for manual updates of each events status in the internal system in timely manner.
- Prepare and record daily report as assigned by supervisor.

Reason for leaving: Contract expired

Position : Coordinator

Company : Hup Yew Sen construction Pte Ltd Period : February 2008 - August 2009

- Supervise, organize and assign to workers to ensure smooth running of the project.
- Monitor and coordinate with project- related activities including, defects work, site installation, site inspection, safety issues, setting to mock up review and support other adhoc duties as assigned by project manager.
- Reporting to project manager of daily site activities.
- Responsible to inventory management, maintain to housekeeping and perform repair activities, in house and on site.

- Liaise with sub contractor, supplier, client and other contractor to ensure smooth of the project and if necessarily to manage defects rectification for completed projects.
- Maintain to logistic management including to packing, quality control, packing list and loading and unloading goods or materials.
- Coordinate with phone, fax, email, Purchasing order, quotation, and admin works.
- Providing of daily manpower report for management to review and support to others documentations.
- Assist in calculation of project cost for submission.

Reason for leaving: Desire a career change

Position : Sales Assistant / Promoter (Part Time)

Company : Nautical Concept Pte Ltd Period : April 2004 – Nov 2006

Responsibilities

- Inventory Management.
- Provided sales training for new employees.
- > Retail management.
- Preparing sales report.

Reason for leaving: To obtain higher education

Position : Sales Coordinator (Part Time)

Company : PT.kilang Papan Indah Jaya (Indonesia)

Period : 2000 March – July 2001

Responsibilities

- Tally product and inventory management.
- Direct sales, processing of invoice and cashiering.
- Assigning workers to carry out work in workshop.

REFERENCES

Remuneration

Last Drawn Salary Expected Monthly Salary Availability Date \$3200 \$3400

Able to commence work immediately